So there is no real correct answer to this quiz if
如果你真的不喜欢钱的话 这个问题对于你来讲好像没有标准答案
you really don't like money, I guess you could prefer not
我猜你可能根本就不需要报酬吧
to be paid at all. The closest thing to a correct
最接近正确答案的回答是 看情况而定
answer is that it depends, and it depends on how you
这取决于你对 biweekly 的解释
interpret the meaning of biweekly. We could look that up in
我们来查一下词典
the dictionary to decide how we should interpret it, and if
看看这个词该怎么解释
we look up biweekly in the dictionary, what we see is
如果你查了词典 就会看见 biweekly 的释义
the definition of biweekly, which is right here. It says happening
就在这儿
every two weeks is the first definition. The
第一个释义是每两周一次
second definition is happening twice a week. If you
第二个释义是每周两次
have the first definition, you'd rather be paid
如果你用第一个释义来解释
weekly, assuming you'd like more money. If you have
你更希望每周获得一次报酬 我们假设你想要更多的钱
the second definition, you'd rather be paid biweekly.
如果采用第二个释义 你更希望每周获得报酬两次
Maybe that's the problem with paper dictionaries, that they're
也许这是纸版词典的问题
not very precise, because they're old things. Let's look
因为都是老古董了 不是很准确
up a more modern dictionary, let's see what Wiktionary
我们再来查一查更现代的词典 看看维基词典怎么说吧
has to say about this. So, here's the Wiktionary entry for
好 这里是维基词典中 biweekly 的词条
biweekly, and if we scroll down, we can see that it has two
向下滚动页面 我们可以看到两种释义
meanings. Occurring once every two weeks, occurring twice a week,
每两周一次和每周两次
this is chiefly in the UK the American
这主要出现在英国
dictionary didn't seem to think that. It seemed to
美国的词典并非如此
think both definitions occurred in both countries. So,
似乎在两个国家都有这样的解释
this is a pretty big problem. If we wrote
所以这是个大问题
a computer program and the program was doing our payroll
如果我们编写一个程序 一个用来操作工资表的程序
and had to decide what it meant to pay someone biweekly,
就必须决定按照 biweekly 付工资意味着什么
we want to make sure it understood that the same
我们必须确定计算机与程序员的理解是一致的
way the programmer did. So that's one important reason why we
所以这就是我们为什么要发明像 Python 这样的语言
need to invent new languages like Python to program computers,
而不是使用我们已经掌握的自然语言
rather than using natural languages that we already understand. And that's
来为计算机编写程序的一个重要原因
because we don't really understand languages like English or Mandarin, that
这是因为我们无法准确理解像英语和汉语这样的自然语言
there's lots of things that different people will understand different ways.
对很多内容的解释会因人而异
And this happens at the granularity of words like biweekly.
这种情况会出现在 biweekly 这类单个单词上
It also happens in complete sentences where there are many different
也会发生在完整句子中
ways to interpret the same phrase. Another reason we don't use
这些句子包含具有多种解释方式的短语
natural languages for programming is that natural languages are actually very
另一个我们不使用自然语言编程的原因是它实在是太繁琐了
verbose. To write a program, we need to describe exactly
为了编写一个程序 我们必须使用非常精确的步骤序列
what the computer should do in very precise sequence of steps.
向计算机准确地描述它应该完成的操作
If we had to describe all those details using a natural
假如我们非得使用自然语言来描述这些细节
language, that would require a huge amount of text. So we'll
就需要使用海量的文本
see soon that with a programming language like Python,
接下来我们可以看到 使用 Python 这样的语言编写程序
we only need a few lines of code to
我们只需要几行代码
describe a complicated thing and describe it in a
就能够以一种非常精确且条理清晰的方式
very precise, step by step way. So I want
描述一个复杂的操作
you to think about as we write programs in
现在请思考 我们在本课中编写的程序
this class, how much more detail you need to
如果使用英语会增加多少细节
actually describe in English, precisely how to do what
使用几行 Python 代码进行精确的描述
we're describing with a few lines of Python code.
是如何做到的